# Juan Pablo Ruiz

(475) 205 9064♦ jpruiz.ec@gmail.com♦ <u>linkedin.com/in/pabloruizsalesforce/</u>

Advanced Salesforce Administrator & Developer II Certified with 7 years of experience in Salesforce environments. Master's degree with proven object-oriented programming techniques, familiar with complete project life cycles, and design skills from inception to completion on projects for Financial, B2B companies, and Nonprofits. Experience with administration and deployment of complex solutions for *Salesforce Sales/Service Cloud, Shield Encryption and Monitoring, Communities and CPQ*.

#### **Technical Skills:**

Salesforce Platforms:

Sales Cloud, Service Cloud, Communities/Experience, Shield Encryption and Monitoring, CPQ

## Salesforce Technologies

- MuleSoft, Salesforce DX, LWC, REST SOAP API, Visualforce, Flow Designer, Approval Process, Process Builder,
- ❖ Import Wizard, Data Export, Data Loader, Workbench

# Languages:

Apex, SOQL, JavaScript, NodeJS, HTML, XML, CSS, Java, Python, Bash Scripting

### Databases:

❖ Postgres, MongoDB, MySQL, Oracle DB, SQL Server

# Methodologies:

CI/CD, Agile Jira, Scrum, SDLC, ER Schema Builder

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Consultant at Korn Ferry/OneMagnify

Remote

Apr 2023 - Present

Salesforce Administrator

- I successfully implemented Conga Quote Generation for Salesforce CPQ, ensuring seamless integration and functionality within our Salesforce environment. I managed prerequisites like enabling Lightning Components, and configured user permissions for accessing SBQQ\_Quote\_c and other Conga objects. Guiding teams through the Document Automation Wizard, I streamlined quote creation, configured templates with Salesforce data merge fields, and integrated eSignature capabilities. This initiative improved efficiency in generating custom quotes and supported timely delivery to clients.
- Implemented Security policies for Salesforce Org Instance on OWD, Sharing Rules, Profiles, Roles, Community Experience, Territories, Salesforce Shield encryption and design data archiving strategies.
- Enhanced data integrity through advanced Java and Salesforce Bulk APIs for efficient batch processing and data cleaning/formatting, which reduced Salesforce Limit issues by 40%.
- Developed seamless Mulesoft transactions for robust integration with external systems.
- Engineered and customized Salesforce solutions utilizing Flow Builder, tailored to specific requirements and improving times of closing Opportunities by 30%.
- Crafted dynamic, user-centric applications using LWC on Salesforce DX, leveraging platform capabilities.
- Spearheaded the execution of effective data management and maintenance strategies to ensure Salesforce Org's peak performance.

Protegrity Stamford, CT Jan 2020 - March 2023

Salesforce Administrator/Developer

• I successfully orchestrated the integration between Salesforce and Oracle E-Business Suite Financials using MuleSoft, enhancing data synchronization and process automation across finance and customer management functions. This initiative involved configuring Salesforce for API access and establishing secure connectivity to Oracle EBS within MuleSoft, utilizing connectors and implementing robust data mapping and transformation strategies. By designing and implementing integration flows in Anypoint Studio, I ensured seamless synchronization of critical financial data, including customer-accounts, sales

- orders, and invoices, product while incorporating business rules and validations to maintain data accuracy.
- Improved system security and user access control, reducing unauthorized access incidents with the implementation of Salesforce Shield which contributed to meeting GDPR requirements.
- Optimized Sales/Services Cloud environments, leading to a 30% improvement in operational efficiencies across teams.
- Enhanced team productivity by 40% through the design and support of a custom app for the Legal team using Salesforce Flow Builder and LWC.
- Directed the migration from Salesforce Classic to Lightning, improving user experience and interface efficiency.
- Deployed a Salesforce Partner Community Site for the Alliances team, boosting engagement and collaboration by over 50%.
- Streamlined the quote-to-cash process with CPQ implementation, leading to an increase in quote accuracy and a reduction in processing time.
- Mastered APEX API coding for Salesforce integrations, enabling sophisticated data exchange and functionality enhancement.

## **ICS/SiriusDecisions**

Wilton, CT

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

Salesforce Administrator

- Managed the seamless migration of Salesforce Org, enhancing system performance and user satisfaction.
- Implemented My Domain and SSO, increasing system security and reducing login issues by half.
- Facilitated the migration of third-party applications, which improved email service efficiency and user satisfaction.
- Tailored Sales and Marketing applications to meet specific user needs, resulting in a 20% increase in user adoption and productivity.

## **Consultant at Logikard**

Remote

Nov 2016 – Dec 2018

Salesforce Administrator/Developer

- Leveraged hands-on experience in force.com to design and implement solutions, resulting in an improvement in business process efficiencies.
- Customized Salesforce pages extensively, including page layouts, formula fields, dependencies, and rules, leading to a 35% increase in user productivity.
- Integrated Salesforce with external platforms like WordPress and CallHub.io, streamlining lead and case management processes, and increasing efficiency via Web-to-Lead and Web-to-Case solutions.
- Conducted comprehensive data management operations, utilizing tools like Import Wizard, Data Export, Apex Data Loader, and Workbench.

## **Building One Community**

Stamford, CT

Feb 2015 - Nov 2016

Administrator and Salesforce User

- Gather functional requirements and processes to design the best solutions for the Salesforce NPSP.
- Deployment of new free packages from AppExchange on Salesforce NPSP org
- Optimized and managed the Worker Center and Skills Development Program operations, improving program delivery and participant satisfaction by 40%.
- Implemented Salesforce customizations that streamlined business processes, leading to a 50% increase in operational efficiency for the Worker Center department.
- Led a team of 5 in transition to use of new project management technologies.

## **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATES**

Master of Science in International Business Management - Manhattanville College, Purchase, NY ESL Class Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

Bachelor of Science Information Systems Engineer - Catholic University, Ambato Ecuador

Salesforce Ranger level on Trailblazer

Salesforce AI Associate

Salesforce Advanced Certified Administrator

Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder

Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I & II

Salesforce Certified Sharing and Visibility Architect